Guide to the Alison Jolly papers, circa 1919-2014
Jolly, Alison papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Alison Jolly papers, circa 1919-2014
8517
Jolly, Alison.
25 cubic feet.264 GB
Printed materials, correspondence, diaries, publications and photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Professional papers, include diaries; correspondence; notes and notebooks; articles and reviews; prints; and photographs.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Alison Bishop Jolly graduated from Cornell in 1958 and received a Ph.D. from Yale University in 1962. As a post-doctoral student at Yale, she pioneered in-depth field research on the behavior and ecology of lemurs in Madagascar, becoming an authority on the ring-tailed lemur. She worked as a research assistant at the New York Zoological Society, and after moving to England as a research associate at Cambridge and the University of Sussex. From 1992 to 1996, she was president of the International Primatological Society, winning its lifetime achievement award in 2010. She was also appointed an officer in the National Order of Madagascar, and in 2006, a newly-discovered mouse lemur species for named in her honor: Microcebus jollyae.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Professional papers, include diaries; correspondence; notes and notebooks; articles and reviews; prints; and photographs.
Children's story books written by Alison Jolly and illustrated by Deborah Rossart as part of the Ako Project to involve and aid primary school teachers in Madagascar; also note cards by Deborah Rossart from the project. Also, woven fabric from Madagascar.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Jolly, Alison.
Subjects:
Lemurs.
Places:
Madagascar -- Description and travel.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Personal family papersclosed until 2044.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Personal Papers
Series II. QMM
Series III. Notes and Papers
Madagascar Diaries
National Geographic Travels
General Documents
Series IV. Photographs
Series V. Audio-visual Material
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Personal Papers
  - Letters to Alison at Yale Location: Yale, 1950-62 (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
    Floyd year out met at Perugia summer 1959, one of circle of friends/lovers. Dick, Marie Achille - Perugia. Idilko Hayes - bosom friend met on Brindisi-Athens ferry 1951, seen at intervals since Victoria cake recipe: "To Kek" made by Greek Maid Victoria 1951-2, staple diet but needs to be cooked in local baker's oven up at the corner of Neophyte Douka.
  - Letters from Margaret Nichol Location: Yale, 1951-52 (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
    Margaret Nichol, friend 1951-52, niece of principal of Greek girls equivalent to Athens college.
  - Letters from Lanier family Yale, 1956-57 (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
    Hosts for junior year in France 1956-57.
  - Letters to Yale Yale, 1950s (Box 19, Folder 3)
    AMK (mother), Jiffy - Janet Farnham, friend since childhood married to Ted Heitmann, Evelyn Hutchinson from Rome, Uncle Ted Bishop (Prudential Insurance salesman), Ann Caristi - Yale room mate 1958-59 left for Florence and married there.
  - Photos Yale, 1950s (Box 19, Folder 3)
    MGB as mace beaver, Cornell and over lawn- left to right AMKB, MGB, AMK, Bill and Betty Miller
  - Letters to Yale, 1950-60 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    Eba, RJ, Kingsbury Chase cousin, H. Kunert, Quinto Maganini - Norfolk Symphony Orchestra, Fabrizio Melano. John Buettner-Janush, diary 1960, MGB, Lanier - president of the Transat, Sigrid - German room mate, Dick Thorington, letter from AMKB and break with Ursula Cowgill. Inaugeration of the France 1962. Conference organised by John Buettner-Janusch, N Y Academy Science 1962.
  - Letters and memorabilia Cornell, 1954-58 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    Gail Beckman, Baldwin friend, later lawyer Margaretta Maganini marriage invitation Louisa DuPont Copeland, Cornell (Theta) friend Janet Rowntree, Cornell friend, later astronomer. Trauma - undergrad humour, MGB, Uncle Ted Bishop, Jiffy - Janet Farnham, Idiko Hayes, Mrs Mary Taber, AMK illustrated Mr Taber's book. Laura Melano (later professor of psychology), Genevieve Gautier - sister of E. Lanier, diary 1957-58
  - Woods Hole Invertebrate Course, 1956; Postcard, letter and catalogue (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Dear Aunt Paulie Cornell, 1956?; Handwritten notes (Box 19, Folder 4)
    Draft of novel? Written in Cornell, since sorority dance scenes. "My handwriting but I've suppressed memory of it."
  - On the Norman Kingdom in Sicily Location: Cornell, 1957; Typed term paper (Box 19, Folder 4)
    On Constanz of Sicily which should be a movie.
  - Junior year in France France, 1956-57; Letters and envelopes (Box 19, Folder 5-6)
    The Seacrests' probably holiday home of Kingsbury's pre WW1. AMK, uncle Ted Bishop, Penny (Eleanor) Sutherland - childhood friend, Margi Clulow, Aunt Ninky (Katherine K.K. Chase) Vatigan stamps from Easter trip to Italy 1957 with AMK, MGB, Francis and Virginia Scheetz (Cornell trustee) and Fabrizio. Ione Gyalistas - younger Baldwinite. Fabrizio and I scandalised her governess by taking her to the Lapin Agile on Montmartre. Janet Rowntree, Lisa Robinson, wife of Richard Robinson, Prof. of Oxford, long term friends of MGB and AMK (were at Cornell in wartime) Margaret Nicholl. Photos: Fabrizio Melano, Henri, Francois and Jean Lanier. Totality of my notes on "Le theme de Faust" Sorbonne course.
  - Diary - junior year in France, 1956-57 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Drawing book - junior year in France, 1956-57 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    Drawing book with rather good picture of room of Lanier with Dagobert the dog, Eloi the cat and Cornell blazer.
  - High school Diary, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    Diary of Scandinavian trip
  - High school letters, 1950s; Letters, notebooks, photos and postcards (Box 19, Folder 8)
    Unitarian church attended with parents, handwriting analysis, postcards from Finland - Scandinavian tour summer 1958, Ile de France 1953, graduation photos Baldwin school - AMK to school. Photos from Ithaca New Year's party with Dmitri Nabokov and Luigi Einauldi, profs sons. Letter about dear Victoria, maid in Athens - Berni Kuboszewski, Bill Sykes death 1950 (I'd been put in 10th grade English in case I couldn't take English in Athens) London 1951, writings at Baldwin, primary school poems by A.B. and Eleanor (Penny) Sutherland.
  - high school diaries, primary school poems, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 9-10)
  - Greece, 1951-52; Sketchbook, diaries and notebooks (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Alison Jolly: A Joyful Celebration, 2014 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - US passports, Zambian driving licence, membership, vaccination and medical cards, c.1960s-2000 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    Includes United Nations certificate, Jersey Wildlife Preservation card
  - Christmas letter, c. 2011 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    AJ's Christmas letter, annotated and changed by daughter Margaretta!
  - AJ's will, 1965; Document and envelope (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Faslane nuclear weapons base, 2007; Letter (Box 21, Folder 12)
    Letter for being arrested at Faslane nuclear weapons base at academic's blockade
  - Medals (Box 16)
  - Dissection kit (Box 16)
  - Honorary Doctorate certificate, University of Antanananarivo, 2012 (Box 16)
  - Letter to Susie [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Letter to Margaretta [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Letter to Margaretta and Susie [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Letter to Richard [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Letter to Richard [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Letter to Susie [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Letter to Margaretta and Susie [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Postcard to Dickon [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1986-7 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Christmas letter [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, RJ New York, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Morris [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly Madagascar, 1986; postcard (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Letter to Margaretta and Susie [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Letter to AMKB [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Letter to Margaretta [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Letter to Margaretta [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Letter to Susie [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Letter to Margaretta [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Letter to Susie and Margaretta [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Dickon's sophomore year [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Letter to Margaretta [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Letter to Dickon [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Letter to Evelyn Hutchinson [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Letter to Margaretta [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1988 ? (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - After AMKB's death [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1988; letter (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Manu [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly Location: Manu Peru, 1988; letter (Box 17, Folder 2)
    John Terborgh's camp in the Manu, Peru
  - Letter to Susie [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Letter to Richard, Mauritius trip [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Postcard to Arthur [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1989? (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Postcard to Dickon [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Postcard to Arthur [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Christmas letter [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Letter to Nidia and reply [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Nidia Sarmiento
  - Christmas letter [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Wedding notes Richard and Nora [RESTRICTED] Location: Hove, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Letter [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Family letter [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Letters from Mexico, Laos and Cambodia [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Christmas invite [RESTRICTED] (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Malaysia, Sarawak, Long House and dyaks Orangutans [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 199? (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Letter to Arthur [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 199? (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Letter to Dickon [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 199? (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Earthwatch letter to Dickon [RESTRICTED] Author: AJ, Earthwatch Berenty, 1991? (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Letter to Richard [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 199? (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Letter to Arthur [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 199? (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Letter to Dickon [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 199? (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Letter to MJ,SAJ, RBJ,AMJ [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Seneca women's peace camp, Seneca NY, letter to Margaretta [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly Location: Seneca, Ithaca, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Durrell House, Tana [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly Antananarivo, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Letter to Richard [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Note to Dickon [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Arthur and Krista's wedding picnic [RESTRICTED] Author: AJ, New York, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - IPS Presidency, Strasbourg [RESTRICTED] Author: RJ, Strasbourg, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Princeton letter to family [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Princeton fax [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, Princeton, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Letter to Richard [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Letter to family [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - MJ in Madagascar [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Christmas letter [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, Bali, Sulawesi, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Letter to MJ,SAJ, RBJ,AMJ [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Departure for Zaire letter to Margaretta [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - More Diary letters [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly: Sark, Barotseland, Zambia, Baringo, 1960s-70s (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - AMKB letters and documents [RESTRICTED] Author: AMKB, 1980s, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Letters from Dickon [RESTRICTED] Author: RBJ, 1980s-1990 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Arthur's letters and notes, with pictures [RESTRICTED], 1980s-1990s (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Letters from Margaretta [RESTRICTED] Author: MJB, 1980s-90s (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Letters from Susie [RESTRICTED] Author: SAJ, 1980s-90s (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Susie in China [RESTRICTED] Author: SAJ, 1980s-90s (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Gill Fowler [RESTRICTED] Author: GJ, up to 1990s (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Cousin's letters and memorabilia [RESTRICTED], up to 1990s (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Friend's letters A-K [RESTRICTED], 1990s (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Friend's letters L-Z [RESTRICTED], 1990s (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Christmas letter and family letter [RESTRICTED] Author: Alison Jolly, 2002/3 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Family and friends [RESTRICTED], Cards, letters and photos (Box 17, Folder 17)
    xiao quiao, Mar, Richard and other Latrobe Batemans, Essies and Laniers, Mary, Ellen Rossiter, Ursula Cowgill, Theo de Mers, Chases Mia and Peter, Leslie Jopson Baldwin School, Didon Faber, Preston Boggess, Takayo Soma, Gall Beckman, John, Gill, Jamie and other Simmonds, Hanta, Josia, Ando, Zo, Tsilavina, Oaks 2012,
  - Sample invitations to Alison's 75th birthday 2012 [RESTRICTED], drawings (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Isabelle Essig letter [RESTRICTED], 2006 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Richard Jolly [RESTRICTED], Cards, letters and photos (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Margaretta Jolly [RESTRICTED], Cards, letters and photos (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Susie Jolly and Kai [RESTRICTED], Cards, letters, photos and drawings (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Arthur Jolly [RESTRICTED], Cards, letters and photos (Box 17, Folder 21)
    I am a giant with anger in my tummy. Version published in Bruner et al. Play 1976
  - Frances [RESTRICTED], Cards, letters, photos and drawings (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Christmas letters [RESTRICTED], Letters (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Family photos and letters [RESTRICTED], 2002-04; Photos and letters (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Family documents [RESTRICTED], 2002-04 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence about Alison's wedding plans [RESTRICTED], 1960s (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Alison Jolly letters [RESTRICTED], 1961-62; Letters and leather wallet (Box 18, Folder 3-4)
  - Letters and documents [RESTRICTED], 1966 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    AMK, MGB, AJ, RJ
  - Letters from AJ, AMK, MGB [RESTRICTED] Location: Cambridge and Old Brewery, 1966-68 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Alison Jolly letters [RESTRICTED] (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Zambia letters [RESTRICTED], 1963-66 (Box 18, Folder 12-14)
  - Alison Jolly letters [RESTRICTED], 1976-77 (Box 18, Folder 9-11)
  - Alison Jollyletters [RESTRICTED] Location: Old Brewrey, 1978-80 (Box 18, Folder 6-7)
  - Personal letters [RESTRICTED], 1980-81 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Family letters and documents, unsorted [RESTRICTED], 1990s (Box 20, Folder 1-12)
    including Zaire and 'The Piano', jury duty, 1994-98.
  - Letters to Alison Bishop, Cornell from Fabrizio Melano [RESTRICTED] Location: Cornell, 1957-58 (Box 18, Folder 15-17)
    Fabrizio Melano, fiance, later Met. Opera director.
  - Letters to Alison Bishop, Cornell from Fabrizio Melano [RESTRICTED] Location: Cornell, 1957-58 (Box 20, Folder 13-15)
- Series II. QMM
  - QMM Location: Madagascar, 1989-1990s; Reports and letters (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - QMM Location: Madagascar, 2000, 2001; Reports and letters (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
  - QMM Location: Madagascar, 2002-2003; Reports, letters, magazines and book (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    The New Broker, Michael Warner
  - QMM Location: Madagascar, 2004; Reports and letters (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - QMM panel Location: Madagascar, 2004; Reports and letters (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - QMM Location: Madagascar, 2005, 2006, 2007; Reports, letters, notebook (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
    QMM Biodiversity committee, QMM notebook Oct 2006, also psychologist's song for Debbie ref. for Roderic Mahasoa
  - QMM Location: Madagascar, 2008, 2010; Reports, letters (Box 7, Folder 7)
    IAP presentations
  - QMM Location: Madagascar, 2010, 2011; Notes and reports (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - QMM Biodiversity commission Location: Madagascar, 2009; Notes and reports (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - QMM undated material Location: Madagascar, Reports, letters and notes (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
  - QMM undated material Location: Madagascar, Reports, letters, notebook (Box 7, Folder 12-13)
  - QMM notes and reports, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 14-15)
  - QMM brochures Location: Madagascar, 1987- 2000 (Box 7, Folder 16-17)
  - QMM brochures Location: Madagascar, 2001-2003 (Box 8, Folder 1-14)
  - QMM brochures Location: Madagascar, 2004-2009 (Box 9, Folder 1-5)
- Series III. Notes and Papers
  - Madagascar Diaries
    - Suicide by Fire. The Duke of Edinburgh's speech at the International Conference on Conservation and Development. Author: Alison Jolly Location: Analabe and Antananarivo, 1985; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Morondava, DeH, Analabe, Duke of Edinburgh, RM, Petter,WWF,Minister Joseph Randrianaso, Maurice Ramarozaka Jaycox, World Bank
    - Dancing by the Rainforest Author: Alison Jolly, 1985; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Ratiarson, David, Ambanizana,Frans Lanting
    - Spring in the Montagne d'Ambre Author: Alison Jolly Location: Montagne d'Ambre, 1985; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Joffreville, Les Roussettes, Georges Randrianasolo,Forester Adany Egbert leigh, Lizzie Leigh, WWF, Jeff Sayer, Karl Schmidt, Udo Hirsch, Ankarafantsika, George Angehr, Benjamin Lenormand, Olivier Langrand, Gin Nodeau, Patrick Thierry,
    - Story Dream The Frozen Professor Author: Alison Jolly, 1985; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - The Pinnacles Author: Alison Jolly, Tsingy de Bemaraha, 1985; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Frans Lanting, Georges Randrianasolo, Bekopaka, Ankarandra, Amoco, Forester Dokobe
    - Death of Children Author: Alison Jolly, Analabe and Antananarivo, 1985; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 1)
      de Campe, Georges Randrianasolo, Frans Lanting, Beroboka, Kirindy, deH, Udo Hirsch, Eva Greer, Hubert Randrianasolo, Jean-Paul Sorg, Udo Hirsch, Ibrahima Fall
    - The First New Reserve in Twenty Years Author: Alison Jolly Location: Beza Mahafaly, 1985; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Lala Rakotovao, Gerry Durrell, Owen Newman, BBC, Sheila O-Connor, Mark Pidgeon, Frans Lanting, Renee Wynn, Petignard, Alison Richard, Eleanor Sterling, WWF, Josef Randrianasolo Minister, RM, Ravelojaona, Andriamampianina, Pothin Rakotomanga, Roland Albignac, Paul Blay, WB, Sam Rae, USAID, Kotokely Kamiha, Rasolondraibe, Quentin Bloxam, Berthe Rakotosamimanana, Jean-Pierre Sorg
    - Julie the Chimpanzee Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty,Zaire, 1985; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 1)
      deH, Didier Foulon, CITES,
    - The Village of Rainy-Rainy, Author: Alison Jolly Andohahela, 1985; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Egbert Leigh, Lizzie Leigh, Sheila O'Connor, Mark Pidgeon, Randriazigzag, Faramalala, Beberonn Randriamampionona, Edmond Manamboatsy,
    - The Chaplet of Pearls, Author: Alison Jolly W. Alton Jones Foundation Tour, 1986; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Olga Hirshhorn, Barthelemi Vaohita, WWF, Pat Edgerton, deH, Dillon Ripley, Mary Ripley, Hella McVay, Peter Lowry, Carleton Swift, RM, Owen Newman, Mark Pidgeon, BBC, Tom Lovejoy, Rekanony, Frans Lanting, Voara Randrianasolo, Bobbie Johnson, Henry Mitchell, Randria Zigzag, Mandinkavelo, Saos, WWF, Julie Keleher, Scott McVay, Gerard Ratsirahonana, Rachel Ravvesandratana, Rabe Ravesandratatana, Jacques Ducand, Jennifer Turnour, Betty Jones, Dick Johnson, Milton Edgerton, Perinet, Roland Albignac, Armand Rakotozafy, Barthelemi Vaohita, Josef Bedo, Jonathan Pollock, Bill Edgerton, Liza Edgerton, John Dransfield, David Cooke, Jim Beach, Armand Rakotozafy, Andriamampianina, Olivier Langrand, Martin Nichol, Berhard Meier, Quentin Bloxam, Nick Lindsay, Bill Lynch, Pat Gates Lynch, Nosy Mangabe, Jeff Keleher, Gerard, Hilary Simons, Paul Dark, Tom Similo, Ratsimilao, Bobbie Johnson, Ratiarson, Bermandiny, Betsimisaraka, Ranomafana, Bernhard Meier, Patricia Wright, Joseph Randrianasolo,
    - The Day the Diadema fell Down, Author: Alison Jolly Ranomafana, 1986; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 1)
      RM, Bernhard Meier, Loret Rasabo, Ambatolahy, Rajerison Emile, Alison Richard, Yves Rumpler, Andre Peyrieras, Patricia Wright, Quentin Bloxam, Lucienne Wilme, Olivier Langrand, Tom Ssoderstrom, Georges Randrianasolo, Petter, Peyrieras, Paul Rarijanona, JIRAMA, Kianjavato, Ranomafana, Hans Preuschoft,
    - Napoleon at St. Catherine's, Author: Alison Jolly St Catherine's Island, 1987; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 1)
      St. Catherine's Island, RM, WWF, Los Angeles Zoo, Jersey Zoo, Long John Hartley, Mme Berthe, Barthelemi, Voara, Ratsirarson, Josef Randrianasolo, Voara, Roland Albignac, FED, DAB, IHF, WB, Frank Larkin, Fred Koontz, Jond Iaderosa, Jim Tamarack, Dan Wharton, Mme Berthe, Patricia Wright, Joe Macedonia, Prithajit Singh, John Harthe, Andrea Katz, John Hartley, Dean White, NASA, Mary Musgrave, RM, Ken Creighton, Louise Emmons, Ben Fried, Robert Oakshott, Ibrahima Fall, Eunice Reading, WB, Basil Blackwilder, Peter Raven, Rajaobelina, Angela Mast, John Constable Mittemeier, Barthelemi, Ratsiraron, Tom Lovejoy, David Challinor, Joan Challinor, Henry Mitchell, Libbie Mitchell, WWF, Bill Reilly, Gretchen Ellsworth, Mary McCutcheon, Bob Hoffman, Bob Faden, Louise Emmons, Murray Gell-Mann, Leslie blay, Nicola Blay, Patricia Lynch, bill Lynch, Olga Hirshhorh, Carleton Swift, Pat Edgerton, Eugenie Weil, Ratssirarson, Mike Robinson, Michael Soule, San Diego Zoo, John Hartley, Diane Brockman, Susan Schafer, Tom Schultz, Amy Neilson,Margo Marsh, Henry Shapiro, John Buetner-janusch, Jonas Salk, Kurt Benirshke, Alan Lieberman, Doug Myers, Los angeles zoo, Michael Soule, Bill Toon, Michael Wallis, Warren thomas, Michael Dee, GLAZA, Macia Hobbs, Mrs Cartwright, Cathleen Cox, MacArthur Foundation, Voara, Jo Andrews, Ben Fried, Missouri botanical Gardens, Bob Sussman, Peter Lowry, MAE, Remy Tiandraza, Parc Tsimbazaza, St. Louis Zoo, Roger Birkel, Pothin, Michelle Sauther, Josephine Andrews, Bob Martins, Georgina Mace, Alan Godlewski, Ratsirarson, Peter Raven, Bob Sussman, Gerry Durrell, Lee Durrell, Lala Rakotovao, John Hartley, Nick Lindsey, Jeremy Mallinson, Jean jaques Petter, Ratsirarson, Odette Mallinson, Sylvia Hartley, David Jeggo, GICS, Margo Rockefeller, Jambo, David Attenborough, Desmond Morris, MJ,
    - Story Dream: the National Geographic covers the Burgess Shale Author: Alison Jolly, 1987; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - The Paris aye-ayes, Author: Alison Jolly Paris, 1987; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Mananara, AMJ
    - Eleanor and the aye-ayes, Author: Alison Jolly Mananara, Ivontaka, 1987; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      AMKB, WWF, Mananara, Jean Jacques Petter, Roland Albignac, Eleanor Stirling, Alison Richard, Nim Tack, Ivontaka,
    - Eleanor and the aye-ayes, Author: Alison Jolly Mananara, Ivontaka, 1987; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Mananara, Ivontaka, Ranovolona, Rabenarivelo, Eleanor Stirling, Felix Rabeza, Morbert, Nim Tack, Monsieur Marcellin, Roger,
    - The First Malagasy, Author: Alison Jolly Diego Suarez, 1987; Manuscript typed (Box 1, Folder 2)